# Hanseok Oh

**Research Interests** 

My main research goal is to build efficient knowledge stores and access systems that can be applied to real-world scenarios. Specifically, I am interested in (1) Retrieval systems that can handle complex conditions and multimodal data (2) how to efficiently manipulate representation space (3) Retrieval augmented Language model.

#### **Education**

## Korea Advanced Institute of Science and Technology (KAIST) @ Seoul Korea

Sep. 2021 - Feb. 2024

Mar. 2014 - Aug.2020

Last updated: Mar 16, 2024

M.S. in Artificial Intelligence

Graduate School of AI | Language & Knowledge Lab

Advisor: Minjoon Seo

SungKyunKwan University (SKKU) @ Seoul Korea

B.S. in Data Science & B.A. in Child and Adolescent Education

Cumulative GPA: 4.0 / 4.5

#### **Selected Publication**

INSTRUCTIR: A Benchmark for Instruction Following of Information Retrieval Models **Hanseok Oh,** Hyunji Lee, Seonghyeon Ye, Haebin Shin, Hansol Jang, Changwook Jun, Minjoon Seo Arxiv 2024 [paper]

Ktrl+F: Knowledge-Augmented In-Document Search

Hanseok Oh\*, Haebin Shin\*, Miyoung Ko, Hyunji Lee, Minjoon Seo

NAACL 2024 [paper]

Zero-Shot Dense Video Captioning by Jointly Optimizing Text and Moment

Yongrae Jo, Seongyun Lee, Aiden SJ Lee, Hyunji Lee, Hanseok Oh, Minjoon Seo

Arxiv 2023 [paper]

Nonparametric Decoding for Generative Retrieval

Hyunji Lee, Jaeyoung Kim, Hoyeon Chang, **Hanseok Oh**, Sohee Yang, Vlad Karpukhin, Yi Lu, Minjoon Seo" ACL 2023 Findings [paper]

Structured Abstract Summarization of Scientific Articles: Summarization Using Full-text Section Information **Hanseok Oh**, Seojin Nam, Yongjun Zhu

JASIST (2022) [paper]

Generative Multi-hop Retrieval Hyunji Lee, Sohee Yang, **Hanseok Oh**, Minjoon Seo EMNLP 2022 [paper] ViSeRet: A simple yet effective approach to moment retrieval via fine-grained video segmentation

Aiden Seungjoon Lee, Hanseok Oh, Minjoon Seo

ICCV 2021 Workshop on Closing the Loop between Vision and Language (CLVL) [paper]

**1st place** at ICCV 2021 VALUE Challenge Retrieval Track [link]

### Experience

**LG AI** Sep. 2023 - Feb. 2024

Research Intern

Working on a retrieval system which can have instruction following ability.

Kakao Enterprise Jul. 2020 - Oct. 2020

Machine Learning Engineer Intern

Worked on large-scale knowledge graph representation learning. Derive insights from large-scale knowledge graphs using Spark.

NAVER, NLP Software Developer Mar. 2020 - Jun. 2020

Software Engineer Intern

Worked on an entity linking engine for the search system. I also extend the Bi-encoder-based entity linking model, BLINK, one of the state-of-the-art entity linking systems into the Korean version.

Undergraduate Research Program, KOFAC

Worked on a fake news detection model based on various machine learning and a word representation method indicating authenticity.

**Military Service** 

Served as a training assistant for the Republic of Korea Air Force Training Wing.

Sep. 2015 - Sep. 2017

#### **Honors and Awards**

- 1st Place, VALUE Challenge Retrieval Track, ICCV 2021
- Korean News Summarization, 3rd prize & Peer evaluation prize, Sungkyunkwan University, Korea (Dec. 2019)
  - o Patent: Way to provide corporate news. Zhu, Oh, Park, Kim. Korean patent application 10-2020-0055691 (2020)
- Essay Generation using GPT-2, 3rd prize, Sungkyunkwan University, Korea (Nov.2019)
- Anomaly Detection using CCTV, 1st prize, Sungkyunkwan University, Korea (Jul.2019)
- KBO Baseball batting average prediction, 3rd prize, Dacon, Korea (Sep.2019)
- Academic Excellence Scholarship, Sungkyunkwan University, Korea (2019)